SOUVIK SARKAR.

Senior Technical Writer

sounix000@gmail.com ◊ (+91) 6360229130 ◊ Portfolio

OVERVIEW

Technical Writer with **9 years** of experience documenting software and APIs for developers and administrators, backed by **4 years** of experience as a **developer**. I develop deep technical content for an optimal developer experience using the docs-as-code paradigm and open-source tools.

SKILLS

Programming Python, Bash, C/C++, Asm
Markup DocBook XML, AsciiDoc
Deployment Docker, Kubernetes
Cloud Google Cloud Platform
VCS Git (GitHub, GitLab)
Images/Diagrams Inkscape, Mermaid.js
Code/Text Editors VSCode, Vim

EMPLOYMENT

SUSE March 2023 - Present

Senior Technical Writer

- · Maintain the SUSE Linux Enterprise guides for security hardening, compliance certifications, performance tuning, virtualization, and deployment.
- · Research, plan, and contribute to transitioning from monolithic guides to topic-based modular documentation for SUSE Linux Enterprise.
- · Collaborate with engineers, release managers, and product managers to realign the SUSE Linux Enterprise documentation with technical and business expectations.
- · Interface with the support engineering team to reinforce existing documentation and create clientspecific knowledge base articles.
- · Participate in peer reviews and mentor new technical writers in the team.
- · Technologies/Tools: SUSE Linux Enterprise, OpenSUSE Leap, Bash, Python, C, Assembly, DocBook XML, AsciiDoc, GitHub, GitLab, VS Code, Vim, JIRA, Confluence Wiki

Red Hat November 2020–March 2023

Senior Technical Writer

- · Lead documentation efforts for OpenShift CI/CD Pipelines, including triaging issues, creating documentation plans, and deciding content strategy.
- · Participated in peer reviews of documents for other products and mentored new technical writers in the team.
- · Collaborated with content strategists and product managers to realign product documentation with upstream documentation.
- · Interfaced with the support engineering team to reinforce existing documentation and create clientspecific knowledge-base articles.
- · Data analyzed to improve documentation coverage, flow, architecture, findability, and accessibility.
- · Technologies/Tools: Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Fedora Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, GCP, AWS, Golang, Bash, AsciiDoc, Markdown, Lucidchart, GitHub, GitLab, VS Code, Vim, JIRA, Tableau, Google Sheets

Ribbon Communications

January 2019–November 2020

Senior Technical Writer

- · Lead documentation efforts for SBC Core, resulting in improved customer satisfaction ratings.
- · Developed documents such as CLI reference and REST API user guide.
- · Participated in peer reviews of documents for other products and mentored new technical writers in the team.
- · Collaborated to revamp the internal style guide for easier onboarding of new technical writers.
- · Technologies/Tools: Proprietary networking and telecom hardware, Debian Linux, C++, C, Bash, OpenStack, AWS, Vim, Confluence Wiki, Snagit, JIRA

FusionCharts (Infosoft Global Pvt. Ltd.)

March 2018–January 2019

Technical Content Writer

- · Developed and reviewed sample applications, code snippets, and content for developer documentation.
- · Implemented automation scripts to improve the operational efficiency of pre-release workflows.
- · Worked with the engineering and marketing teams to create and publish technical articles on third-party websites and blogs.
- · Technologies/Tools: macOS, JavaScript (Node.js, Vue.js, React.js), VS Code, Vim, Markdown, Lucid-chart, GitHub, Trello

Tata Elxsi

June 2016–March 2018

Consultant Technical Writer

Contractor for Ribbon Communications

- · Created and maintained Quick Start tutorials, API guides, User guides, and Release Notes.
- · Technologies/Tools: Proprietary networking and telecom hardware, Debian Linux, C++, C, Bash, OpenStack, AWS, Vim, Confluence Wiki, Snagit, JIRA

Agaze Technologies

September 2015–May 2016

Software Engineer

- · Developed internal and client-facing applications, focusing on back-end implementation.
- · <u>Technologies/Tools</u>: Ubuntu Linux, Python (Django, Flask), JavaScript (Node.js, React.js), Google <u>Cloud Platform (App Engine)</u>, Sublime Text, Vim

Freelance/Self-employed

July 2012-August 2015

Web Developer

- · Developed websites, administered systems, and wrote technical content for blogs as a ghostwriter.
- · Technologies/Tools: Ubuntu Linux, Python, JavaScript, Sublime Text

RECOGNITIONS

Red Hat - Several peer-to-peer awards from team members (including engineering) for collaboration and commitment to excellence.

Ribbon Communications - Motivate Award (2019-2020) for extraordinary performance.

Tata Elxsi - Customer Appreciation Award (2016-2017) based on client recommendation.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology

2014